<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content"><channel><title>Vivek Selvaraj</title><description>Software Developer</description><link>https://vivek.dev</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 23:46:32 +0530</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 23:46:32 +0530</pubDate><ttl>250</ttl><atom:link href="https://vivek.dev/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vivek.dev/posts/2020-12-17-Inception</guid><title>Inception</title><description>Where it all started</description><link>https://vivek.dev/posts/2020-12-17-Inception</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 22:58:00 +0530</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Stacktrace</h2><p>I’ve been a long time listener of the <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/stacktrace/id1359435443?mt=2">Stacktrace</a> podcast by <a href="https://twitter.com/johnsundell">John Sundell</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/_inside">Gui Rambo</a>. It's a podcast where they talk about Apple and what projects they are working on. Which are predominantly iOS and Swift projects. And I don't know Swift.</p><p>I started listening to Stacktrace when it used to be a podcast where they discuss Apple's leaks, news and rumours from a developer's perspective. I got hooked immediately. Overtime, it evolved into a podcast where they discuss Apple, Swift, their projects and indie development. This is where I first heard about <a href="https://github.com/JohnSundell/Publish">Publish</a>.</p><h2>Publish</h2><p>It was late last year, when John was talking about his precious little project and how he is going to make it open source eventually. It's a static site generator built with Swift for Swift developers. It was also the time where I was jumping from tutorial to tutorial trying to learn Swift and iOS development.</p><p>He had built his website <a href="https://www.swiftbysundell.com">Swift by Sundell</a> using Publish. No JavaScript. Just pure HTML and CSS. That site was blazingly fast. The load time was almost instant. Then I decided. If I ever launch a website, I'll have it JavaScript free.</p><h2>Catalyst</h2><p>The time has come. I have decided to generate my site using Publish. With the limited knowledge of Swift that I had gained through the first 12 days of <a href="https://www.hackingwithswift.com/100/swiftui">100 Days of SwiftUI</a>, I was able to create a starter website, and customize it to my needs.</p><p>I've always wanted to try my hand at blogging, but I never thought I was good enough to write. A recent <a href="https://twitter.com/twostraws/status/1330559062803673088">tweet</a> by Paul Hudson (the guy behind 100 Days of SwiftUI) was the catalyst that pushed me to do it.</p><p>Welcome to <a href="https://vivek.dev/">vivek.dev</a> 🙏</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>